komplett.ie 2012-12-09

# Komplett.ie – The internetshop in Ireland

**Shopping** | Payment | Delivery | Support & returns | About us | What do we offer? | 

* * *

The answer to  
your question not here?  
Please contact  
us. 

* * *

## Privacy Policy

### Komplett Privacy Statement

Download this Privacy Statement as a [PDF-file](http://content.komplett.ie/KB-KOMPIE/documents/terms/privacy_ie_new.pdf) | [Word-file](http://content.komplett.ie/KB-KOMPIE/documents/terms/privacy_ie_new.doc)

This pirvacy statement has been made by:  
**Company:** KBV BV  
**URL:** www.komplett.ie

Please read the following Privacy Statement to understand how we use and protect your personal data. By using this site, you consent to the collection, use and transfer of your information under the terms of this privacy statement.

For the purposes of your use of www.komplett.ie, your data controller is Komplett BV and the contact details are Komplett BV, Kleveringweg 4, 2616 LZ, Delft, The Netherlands and [service@komplett.ie](mailto:service@komplett.ie).

You may use these contact details, if you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, or the use of your personal data. If you wish us to stop using your personal data in any way, please send an email to: [service@komplett.ie](mailto:service@komplett.ie). or login to your Komplett account and deselect the option that you do not want to receive any information anymore.

**Collection Of Personal Data**

When you shop with us, we ask you to provide us with personal data, such as a password, email address, home address and credit card or other information so that we can invoice you for and deliver the items you have ordered via the carrier you choose, as well as contact you regarding your order.

We may collect information about you from emails or letters you send to us. 

We also collect and keep information regarding which categories or products visitors are looking at or searching for, to be able to learn what our customers are interested in as well as improve our assortment and offers. 

To combat fraud we may gather identifying information about the computer running your browser software. This information includes but is not necessarily limited to, the IP address. 

Please also read **Cookies** below.

**Use of your personal data and disclosure of personal data**

We use your personal data to supply you with products and services ordered by you, to bill you and to contact you about an order. We also analyse information provided by you and others to help us administer, support and improve our business. 

We may use your personal data to contact you, to tell you about important changes or developments to the Site or about our services or to obtain your views on our services. 

Information we collect regarding which categories of products visitors are looking at or searching for, is used to learn what our customers are interested in, so as to improve our assortment of products and offers of products. It is also used to show related products or send you related offers (if you have explicitly consented to this) and also to produce traffic statistics for capacity planning.

Where you have agreed, we may use your personal data to let you know about other products and services which might be of interest to you. This contact may be by post, telephone or fax or email. If you want to stop receiving information about other products and services, you can opt out at any time by contacting us at [service@komplett.ie](mailto:service@komplett.ie) or login to your Komplett Account and deselect the option that you do not want to receive any information anymore (Login on your account, select ?Edit contact persons? on the bottom of the page, then click your ?Name? in the blue bar.Finally, on the right side of the screen tick the box underneath the header ?Send information about;?)

**Disclosure to others**

The personal data and information you provide will not be shared or sold to third parties. Also your personal data is not accessible by third parties. 

We may pass aggregate information on the usage of our site to third parties but this will not include information that can be used to identify you.

You acknowledge and agree that your personal data may be made available to third parties ( including to Regtel), in order for us to comply with law, regulatory requirement or legal process, in order to protect and defend our rights and to enforce the terms and conditions and any Agreement resulting therefrom. You agree that the IP address may be supplied to regulatory authorities in connection with fraud or other formal investigations and we undertake to keep such information confidential except for disclosure to such authorities in connection with such investigations. 

You agree that if you send offensive or objectionable content or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on the Site, that that we can use whatever information that is available to us about you to stop such behaviour. This may involve informing relevant third parties such as law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour.

In order to prevent fraud, to check your identity or prevent money laundering, we may search the files of credit reference agencies. They will record any credit searches on your file. We may also disclose details of how you conduct your account with us to such agencies. The information may be used by lenders for making credit decisions about you, for fraud prevention, money laundering prevention and for tracing debtors

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small file sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer?s hard drive to identify you as the user of the Site. Many internet sites uses cookies. 

We use and require a cookie for you to register and place an order. It is possible to view products without using cookies. We also endeavour to create a permanent cookie which will be used to recognise you when you return. This cookie can be deleted by logging off your account.

Additionally, our Site uses cookies to keep track of your access to the Site. We may also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests. You can set your browser preferences to reject all cookies but this will prevent you from using most customised services and you have to repeatedly enter log in information in order to use some services. Cookies make your experience easier by saving your preferences. 

**Security**

We employ security measures to protect your personal data from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage.

**Changes to our Privacy Statement**

Any changes to our Privacy Statement in the future will be posted to the Site and where appropriate, through email notification. 

**Right to be supplied with a copy of personal data**  
You have the right to be given a copy of your personal data which you may have supplied to us via the Site. To exercise this right, you must make your request in writing, post it and send it to our address as specified above and include with the request, a copy of your passport, a copy utility bill which will verify your address and enclose a fee of Euro 6.35. A request will be dealt with as soon as possible and will take not more than 40 days to process.

**Rectification, Retention and deletion of personal data.**

You also have the right to have inaccurate personal data corrected. If you discover that we hold inaccurate personal data about you, you can (1) logon to your Komplett Account and change your personal data to the correct data at any given time, or (2) have a right to instruct us to correct that information. Such an instruction must be in writing and will not take more than 40 days to process. 

We are obliged to keep information about you for accounting, duty and vat compliance purposes and for any possible warranty/return handling, so this information cannot be deleted. We also retain personal data as required to meet our record keeping obligations under other laws and regulations. Additionally for safety reasons, we need to keep details of the IP address used to place the order.

If you pay by credit-card, we will for safety reasons, keep the card number for a limited period of time. The credit card companies demand that we keep the card number for effective handling of any possible problems regarding debiting, cancelling a reservation and \ or crediting. We never keep safety codes or passwords in relation to credit card payment. The card number is deleted after the limited period.

In certain circumstances you may also request that personal data which you have supplied via the Site be deleted, if we do not have a legitimate reason for retaining the personal data. We are not entitled to charge for dealing with such a request and we must comply within 40 days of the receipt of such a request. To exercise this right you would generally be expected to identify some contravention of data protection law in the manner in which the Site processes the personal data concerned. 

In each case, you must make your request in writing, post it and send it to our address as specified above and include with the request, appropriate information as we determine that will identify you and your address.

**Other websites**

This Privacy Statement only covers the Komplett.ie website. Other links within this site to other websites or framed third party sites within the Komplett.ie website are not covered by this Statement.
